NIKHIL GUNTI

1315, W.3rd Ave, A3, Stillwater, OK

□ 405-762-0337 | ☑ nikhil.gunti@okstate.edu | ☑ nikhilgunti | 匝 gunti-nikhil/

Professional Summary

Business acumen with 2+ years of experience in product development domain having hands-on SQL, Python, R, and other technologies. Strong working knowledge performing data analysis & building models using Pandas, Numpy, Scikit and developing Tableau dashboards.

Education

Oklahoma State University, Stillwater, OK

CGPA: 4.0

MASTERS IN BUSINESS ANALYTICS & DATA SCIENCE

Aug. 2019 - May. 2021

JNTUH College of Engineering, Hyderabad, India

CGPA: 3.5

B.Tech in Electronics and Communication Engineering

Aug. 2013 - May. 2017

Technical Skills & Certifications

- Programming Languages: C/C++, SAS, SQL, R, Python, Matlab, Verilog
- Tools: R Studio, Tableau, JMP, Power BI, Postgre SQL, Visual Studio 2019, Google Colab
- **Certifications:** Computer Vision Nanodegree- Udacity, SAS Programming Certified Specialist, 'Become a Data Scientist' LinkedIn course, 'Data Visualization: Story Telling' LinkedIn course, 'Innovation and Information Technology Management' by IIM Bengaluru

Work Experience

Spears School of Business - OSU

Stillwater, OK

GRADUATE TEACHING ASSISTANT

Jan. 2020 - Present

 Assist Dr. Jihoon Jhang for the course 'MKTG 3323-Consumer and Market Behavior' and Dr. Ritchie Liu for the course 'MKTG 4683-Managerial Strategic Marketing' with classroom instructions, exams, grading, record keeping, and research papers

Wipro Limited Hyderabad, India

Project Engineer Aug. 2017 - Jul. 2019

- **Data Analytics** Ran Naive Bayes & logistic regression models for multi-class text classification based on case description. Also, analyzed the factors behind lease cases and tried to predict the number of lease issues for next quarter.
- Lease Accounting Consulting Interacted with clients all over the world and assisted them with both functional & technical issues of the product IBM TRIRIGA, specifically real estate module of the product
- Case Resolution Debugged platform & application issues of product and resolved 234 client cases in a year (2nd in team of 19)
- **Content Creation** Created and developed training content of 8.5 hours for Lease Accounting module of the TRIRIGA product from the scratch solitary, which is being consumed by most of the Fortune 500 companies and their clients
- Team Management Promoted to team lead and entrusted with responsibility to manage a team of 3 experienced professionals

Academic Projects

Deep Learning and Computer Vision

OSU

RESEARCH STUDENT - INDEPENDENT STUDY

Dec. 2019 - present

- Working on research project to understand visual world beyond recognition or captions without the need for explicit human supervision through expensive annotations by developing self-supervised predictive learning for video event segmentation
- · Submitted research paper 'Skin Cancer detection using Deep Learning techniques' to Western region SAS conference
- Built various deep learning models using predefined nets like Resnet50, VGG16 etc on Keras, Tensorflow & Pytorch frameworks

MetroTech Center Retention OSU

DATA ANALYST Aug. 2019 - Nov. 2019

- Analyzed past 5 years of student survey responses to improve satisfaction rate. Interesting correlations between the variables influencing retention rate were drawn for further analysis
- · Built Multinomial logistic regression model to identify significant factors and created interactive visualization dashboards

Customer Feedback Analysis of Apple Products

OSU

1

Data Analyst

ТЕАМ МЕМВЕК

Sept. 2019 - Nov. 2019

• Scraped data from Twitter & other social media websites and performed web content mining to analyze user's feedback on recently launched Apple iPhones. Used libraries like NLTK, Gensim to perform sentiment analysis & named entity of customer reviews

Number Plate Detection using MATLAB

JNTUH Sept. 2016 - Dec.2016

• Input image is processed and performed localization of number plates to detect characters present on it

· Used simple colour conversion edge detection and removal of noise with application of median filter as one of the operators

Leadership & Management Roles_

- Vice President: My role as VP for Business Analytics Student Association (BASA) includes organizing technical workshops, meetups, con-necting BASA members with alumni network
- **Community Development Volunteer:**Worked with 'YouthForSeva' to stabilize the financial status of impoverished kids in public schools by enabling them to bag scholarships and conducted career empowerment sessions & weekend classes on maths and science

APRIL 30. 2020 NIKHIL GUNTI · RÉSUMÉ